Speaker 1: It's Thursday, February 8th, 2024.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, we are reviewing Super Magfest 2024.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh, you know, a little while ago, I had that opening bit on Geek Nights, that anecdote of.
Speaker 1: I actually asked the dude on the subway who had his phone out just at full volume, like, "Hey, what's
Speaker 1: up?".
Speaker 1: And, you know, he explained you can't plug headphones into phones anymore and didn't understand modern technology.
Speaker 1: and that seemed to be the extent of it.
Speaker 1: So, uh, it's definitely I've noticed since the return from COVID compared to before, like, I encounter so many people doing this in my daily life.
Speaker 1: Like, every day there's someone doing it on the subway.
Speaker 0: I also have perceived and not quantified an increase in the behavior of people using the speaker on their phone in a public environment where other strange people are subjected to the sound.
Speaker 1: So, on the previous trip, when we went to Vail, I encountered it in a bunch of situations I have never encountered it before to the point that it is definitely a thing and I was googling around to see if, like, yeah, there's a million op-eds and it's not just phones really loud.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of evidence just like that article you pointed us at a while ago around how, yes, people are literally driving worse and crashing more since COVID.
Speaker 1: Antisocial behavior in public in America seems to be just growing in general in all public spaces and there seems to be some evidence this is happening.
Speaker 1: But, so, we go to the airport to fly to Colorado and we get on the plane and a dude gets on the plane and is just watching YouTube videos at full volume on his phone on the speaker in the seat behind us and everyone on the plane around us are all kind of looking at each other.
Speaker 0: But on a plane there are flight attendants who will stop that shit.
Speaker 1: So the flight attendant didn't say shit.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Did anyone ask them to?
Speaker 1: So, what I suspect was happening, because this is what I was thinking, is basically, like, I kind of caught eyes with, like, all the people sitting around us and we all kind of, like, looked at each other and, like, nodded a little and kind of, like, looked at the guy.
Speaker 1: And the flight attendants also, like, I caught the eye of the flight attendant and I kind of, like, did the head nod toward the guy and she looked at me and she kind of sighed and nodded, but no one did anything.
Speaker 1: And I think the flight attendants and the other people around me were thinking what I was thinking.
Speaker 1: And I was thinking, the person doing this is more likely than the average person, because they're already engaging in a very antisocial behavior, to be the kind of person where if they're asked not to do it, will cause us all to have to de-board the plane while the police arrest them.
Speaker 1: And none of us want to be delayed on our flight to Vail because there aren't that many flights to Vail.
Speaker 1: And everyone on this plane is flying to Vail to ski, probably with a non-refundable timeshare like we had rented.
Speaker 1: So, I just wait and it's, like, it is so loud, it is, like, fascinating.
Speaker 1: And this dude is just, like, totally in his vibe, ignoring everyone.
Speaker 1: He's got his, like, hat pulled down and just doing his thing.
Speaker 1: But when the flight said, "Alright, we're going to take off," he didn't turn it off and he just kept watching the YouTube videos.
Speaker 1: He just clearly had not even put his phone in airplane mode, but the flight attendants are in their jump-seats, so they can't do anything about it.
Speaker 1: And his YouTube stopped working after the plane started to take off, for the reasons you can imagine.
Speaker 1: And thankfully, at this point, the dude seems to have just passed out and slept for the entire flight.
Speaker 1: And then when we landed, he immediately started watching YouTube again on his phone, at full volume.
Speaker 1: Then we get off the plane and we get on the little shuttle to get to where we're going to pick up our rental car in Denver.
Speaker 1: And on the shuttle, there was an old man clearly watching, like, a video of his kids at full volume with the speakers on the phone.
Speaker 1: And there was a woman watching YouTube videos at full volume on the phone while also carrying two Stanley Cups.
Speaker 1: Like, the Stanley Cups.
Speaker 1: She was carrying them outside of her luggage and they were wrapped and it was a thing.
Speaker 1: And I just kept encountering this the entire trip.
Speaker 1: People were doing it on the ski lifts, people were doing it in the lodges, to the point that it's clearly a trend and I don't know what to do about it.
Speaker 1: It's just people being kind of antisocial and rude in a way that I don't feel strongly enough to engage with them.
Speaker 1: And I feel like this is just how public spaces are going to be for the first thing in the future.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, if you look around the world, right, there are some countries that are famous for how everyone is so strictly behaving.
Speaker 0: However true or not true those stereotypes are.
Speaker 1: And then there's Philadelphia.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then there are countries that are stereotyped the other way, right?
Speaker 0: And you can often see this, especially in transportation.
Speaker 0: It's like some cities, everyone's obeying the lights and other places.
Speaker 0: People just drive like, you know, Cairo is famous for having like the worst traffic.
Speaker 0: People just driving everywhere, no traffic control, just free for all, you know, whatnot, right?
Speaker 0: And so it's like, well, if the United States, you know, was, you know, sort of in between those two places, right?
Speaker 0: And I guess it's going towards the other kind.
Speaker 1: Which leads to what I encountered on my way home from work today on the seventh train, because some dude is just playing like a reggaeton on his phone at full blast.
Speaker 1: And another guy standing near him actually like pretty politely is like, hey, buddy, could you turn that down?
Speaker 1: Like, it's pretty loud.
Speaker 1: And the dude flips his absolute shit at this guy.
Speaker 1: And we all had to like kind of clear out of the train at the next station because it looked like a fight was going to break out.
Speaker 1: So this is partly why, like, I don't even engage with anyone.
Speaker 1: Like, I'm not even going to politely ask someone who's acting in this way to calm down.
Speaker 1: I just get away from them or ignore it because...
Speaker 0: But then on the other hand, right, they win.
Speaker 0: They do win.
Speaker 0: That's the general principle that is like.
Speaker 0: underlying a lot of the problems in society, capitalism or no, is that people who are willing to, who are confrontational and are willing to fight or get mad or whatever often get their way.
Speaker 1: Well, because if I'm on the subway and I've had many situations...
Speaker 0: But not just in small situations, also in big situations, right?
Speaker 0: The company that's willing to be litigious can.
Speaker 0: sometimes they lose because they're so outlandish.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But a lot of times it's like they'll just win even when they're wrong because they're willing to fight.
Speaker 1: I mean, case in point, you notice we don't do the Utena videos on YouTube anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Guess why?
Speaker 0: So... So just being an angry... So, you know, it's like if you don't want, you know, the angry people to just win in society, you have to basically at some point suffer.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: The hassle of confronting them and dealing with them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I guess with the stakes...
Speaker 0: You'll take damage when doing so.
Speaker 0: But it's like, yes, sometimes the only way to stop someone from doing damage is someone else needs to make a sacrifice and, you know...
Speaker 1: It's tough, though, because the stakes for something as small as this loud antisocial behavior with phones in public, the fact that...
Speaker 0: Yeah, the stakes for that are low, but the stakes for someone being murdered on the street by a car...
Speaker 1: Oh, yes.
Speaker 1: But if the stakes are low on that, but yet I have three times since Covid seen someone ask someone to turn their phone down and the person who was asked literally either attacks them or threatens to attack them or flips the fuck out in a dangerous way.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: To where I would not be willing to antagonize an antisocial person on the subway.
Speaker 0: No, that's not worth it for those stakes.
Speaker 0: But the point is...
Speaker 1: But it means the subway is just going to have people playing reggaeton at full volume on their phones forever.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a lot of, you know, sci-fi biz out there.
Speaker 0: that's, you know, there's a frequent sci-fi tale is like the Minority Report tale, like, oh, are you going to arrest people for pre-crime?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, are you going to be doing that?
Speaker 0: And it's like, and they're like, no, you can't be doing that.
Speaker 0: That's no good.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Obviously.
Speaker 0: But I feel like we, there is, I don't know what it is.
Speaker 0: I'm not a psychologist or a doctor.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But there are clearly people who temporarily, permanently, genetically, environmentally, for whatever reason, are angry people.
Speaker 0: Are they always angry?
Speaker 0: Are they temporarily angry?
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: They're the kind of person who gets angry.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Two people could be in the same exact situation.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're stuck in a long line or something.
Speaker 0: And one of them just gets super mad about it.
Speaker 0: And the other person, they might be upset, but isn't going to be angry or violent or dangerous.
Speaker 1: Well, similarly, the kind of person who gets mad in traffic and might yell "fuck you" or flip someone off versus the kind of person who road rages.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's just like there's this, you know, so I feel like there is a cluster there.
Speaker 1: It's a combination of poor impulse control and a few other factors.
Speaker 1: And there's a personality type that there's a name for it.
Speaker 1: Similar to that right-wing authoritarian personality type.
Speaker 1: Like these are fairly well-documented personality types.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But I'm sure that, you know, people who have, you know, studied psychology, psychiatry, etc.
Speaker 0: know much more about anger than I do.
Speaker 0: But whatever it is, I would not be opposed to some sort of evidence-based plan of action to basically, you know, impose something upon people who are, even if they haven't done anything, even if the people have not done anything yet.
Speaker 0: People who are angry should be in some way forced into some sort of help or some sort of program or something that is evidence-based and effective at preventing them from harming others with their angry ways.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the one where we're definitely assuming it is not righteous anger.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But we're talking about, you know, the flip.
Speaker 1: The dude who flips the fuck out over nothing and tries to punch someone over nothing.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So I think a line...
Speaker 0: But a righteous anger is a temporary anger, right?
Speaker 0: You can look at the cause of it and say...
Speaker 1: Yeah, someone who's experiencing systemic racism and fights back.
Speaker 1: That is a very different situation.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That person will also, if the systemic racism miraculously, even though it won't, if it miraculously goes away, that person would stop being angry.
Speaker 0: They would be like,
Speaker 0: "Yes!"
Speaker 0: And they would be reveling, right?
Speaker 0: It's like the angry person who has this true anger, whatever causes it, whatever it truly is, is always angry, right?
Speaker 0: No matter, you know, it's not about a thing, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, even if that, even if they weren't waiting in a line...
Speaker 1: They move on to the next grievance.
Speaker 1: They move on to the next road rage.
Speaker 1: There's a reason why when someone gets arrested for road rage, there's usually a long history of convictions for road rage.
Speaker 1: So a good line there.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you look like a beekeeper and they're like, "Oh yeah, these bees over here, I had to kill them all because they're just angry
Speaker 0: bees.".
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: It's like, "And these bees, they don't sting so much.
Speaker 0: They're
Speaker 0: fine.".
Speaker 1: So I think a good line to use an example because you want to be concrete because everything you described in theory is discussable, but of course there is a very easy way to misapply everything you just said.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: That's why.
Speaker 1: So, an example would be, road rage.
Speaker 1: If someone commits a crime that is classified as road rage, there should be an extreme intervention in their lives around rage issues, psychotherapy, permanently, not permanently, but indefinitely suspended driver's license.
Speaker 1: Like, if you try to use a car to hurt someone, you can't drive.
Speaker 0: If you are identified as an angry person, there's like a long list of things.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't be allowed to work with any dangerous equipment.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't be allowed to have any guns, obviously, right?
Speaker 1: Except, so in the US, we've started to pass these red flag laws where if you have certain kinds of impulse control or rage issues or you've committed certain crimes with high violent recidivism in the past, like domestic violence, one of the highest recidivism rate crimes in the world, you're not allowed to have a gun unless you get a court order saying that you're sane again or fine again or whatever, but now in America, only blue states have those laws and red states have undone or blocked all those laws and it becomes
Speaker 0: a political issue.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm glad.
Speaker 0: You know, they keep, you know, they keep busing migrants over here.
Speaker 0: Why don't we bus angry people to the red states?
Speaker 1: Just bus all the Republicans in New York to Texas.
Speaker 0: Like, we have exiled you to Oklahoma.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: It's like, no prison.
Speaker 0: We don't need prison.
Speaker 0: You just have to go to Oklahoma.
Speaker 0: You can't come back.
Speaker 1: This is, you know, I'm really glad, unfortunately, that Pac South died because had it continued, we would have had to boycott it because I will not go to Texas.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not going to Texas.
Speaker 1: So in some slightly less sad stuff, we're talking about the news, the Super Bowl is this weekend and I think you said it best and I feel the same way.
Speaker 1: In my entire life, I have never been less enthused about a Super Bowl than I am for this Super Bowl that I can remember.
Speaker 1: Like, I could not care less.
Speaker 1: The Lions didn't make it.
Speaker 0: I could care less.
Speaker 1: If the Lions or the Bills had made it to the Super Bowl, I would have cared the most I have ever cared.
Speaker 0: However, I have never, to this point, cared as little as I do now in my 40-whatever years, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like my caring can continue to decrease.
Speaker 0: We got room, but we're at the bottom.
Speaker 0: We're as low as we've been in four decades.
Speaker 1: We found a local minima.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: So yeah, what, Kansas City?
Speaker 1: I feel like at our party, we're just going to have the game on in the background and mostly just do other things.
Speaker 0: So yeah.
Speaker 0: Which number is this year's Super Bowl?
Speaker 1: 58.
Speaker 1: L-V-I-I-I.
Speaker 0: L-V-I-I.
Speaker 0: So it's 58.
Speaker 0: So I've been alive for most of the Superb Ls.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's funny.
Speaker 1: When I was a kid, I just just like a little kid, I assumed because, you know, we're a hockey town.
Speaker 1: So I cared a lot about the Stanley Cup.
Speaker 1: And as a little kid, I knew Lord Stanley's Cup is fucking ancient.
Speaker 1: It's so old.
Speaker 0: Way older than the Super Bowl.
Speaker 1: Like it appeared before World War One happened.
Speaker 1: There was a little kid like, yeah, that is an artifact.
Speaker 1: Like that's an Indiana Jones kind of thing.
Speaker 1: And I just assumed as a little kid that every other sports thing was similarly old.
Speaker 1: I didn't know the Super Bowl was new.
Speaker 0: The oldest one that I remember is Super Bowl 21, which is from 1987.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: When the Giants won and I was five.
Speaker 1: Terminator one came out years before that Super Bowl.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: As we learned at the hockey game.
Speaker 1: So yeah, whatever Super Bowl, someday the Lions will make it and then I'll be really excited once.
Speaker 1: Some other news.
Speaker 1: We could probably skip my extreme news because we are about our lines because we talked a lot about social inequality and anger.
Speaker 1: But you've got some news about Sony erasing digital libraries.
Speaker 0: Well, we all knew that Sony bought Funimation, Crunchyroll, merge them all together.
Speaker 0: We talked about that, like when it happened.
Speaker 0: And it's sort of actually happening now, like more completely.
Speaker 1: It's another unfortunate consolidation in the hellscape of late capitalism.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, the sports TV networks having a similar thing going on to anyway.
Speaker 0: But what's happened is there was a program in which if you bought some Funimation DVDs that they would include a code.
Speaker 0: And you could go to Funimation dot com with the code and basically get a digital copy of the DVD that you already bought.
Speaker 0: So if you bought, you know, I mean, one piece episode 10 or whatever, you put the code in.
Speaker 0: And then if you go to Funimation dot com, there are the episodes and say, yeah, you got the DVD, you could watch that.
Speaker 0: But you've also got the digital copy by going to this website.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You're sort of buying digital and physical at the same time.
Speaker 0: But because of this merger, right, most of the content that was sort of streaming as part of your Funimation sub is on Crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it's not every show, but it's basically, you know, if your sub is going to transfer over, you'll still have access to all the, you know, subscribe stuff.
Speaker 0: But that obviously the technology for the codes and these permanently watchable shows does not exist on Crunchyroll because they don't do that.
Speaker 0: And so you're going to lose that if you write.
Speaker 0: So people who maybe bought the DVD and then threw the DVD away or didn't rip it, or if it's not just if it doesn't happen to be something that you can also stream, they're going to lose that digital copy that they technically speaking paid for.
Speaker 0: And that's that.
Speaker 0: So, you know, people are mad, I guess, rightfully, but it's like piracy is fully justified here.
Speaker 1: Like what else can I say?
Speaker 0: I mean, there were some vague promises of using words like forever.
Speaker 0: But, you know, obviously, if you probably read the EULA, it probably doesn't actually say forever.
Speaker 1: There's only one service I would ever trust to be effectively forever.
Speaker 1: And that is Steam.
Speaker 1: only because of their strong history of not fucking that up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Steam has been around for already this long and has never fucked it up.
Speaker 1: Not even once.
Speaker 0: Not even once.
Speaker 0: And so it's like it doesn't even need to be forever.
Speaker 0: This needs to be as long as I live.
Speaker 1: Fuck them kids.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: As long as I can live to the end of Steam.
Speaker 1: But this is extra sad, partly because as we learned just a little while ago today, some of our friends.
Speaker 1: So this is a public service announcement for all of you out there.
Speaker 1: A lot of people seem to think that bit rot and decay of physical discs like DVDs only happens to CD-Rs and CD-RWs.
Speaker 1: No, it happens to press commercial CDs and DVDs as well.
Speaker 1: It takes longer, but it happens.
Speaker 1: If you have a CD from the earliest days of CDs, there's a decent chance it has started to degrade.
Speaker 1: Have you used it recently?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: People seem to, you know, are like, "Ah, physical media.
Speaker 0: I'll have this
Speaker 0: forever.".
Speaker 0: It's like, "No, not really.
Speaker 0: Even if you take really good care of them, maybe I don't even know if vacuum storing them would be...".
Speaker 1: It would not, because in some cases it's the glue that holds that shield, the clear part in front of the metal part, that glue will degrade.
Speaker 1: Or the glue that holds the metal part onto the back will degrade.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So it's like, that shit doesn't last forever.
Speaker 1: Nothing lasts forever but a digital copy that is a file that you can continuously refresh by moving it around between devices that can store digital files.
Speaker 0: There's also, we've talked about things like HD Rosetta or whatnot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a Cardassian memory stick.
Speaker 0: Designed to last impossibly long times.
Speaker 0: But regardless, it's like, the best way to have media, I think, in the current times, is obviously, if it's piratable or downloadable by people in some way, then that means that copies of it will flourish, and as long as someone's got it, you're good.
Speaker 0: That's the mechanism that basically Git, the source code version control system uses, is that, yeah, anyone who checks out the code has a full copy.
Speaker 0: So like, if your company's headquarters explodes, and Amazon explodes, if one of your employees' laptops is still out there, you still get your source code.
Speaker 0: And then two, fucking library, right?
Speaker 0: The library is basically the best of all worlds.
Speaker 0: It's free, like piracy, you don't gotta pay anything.
Speaker 0: They have a mega collection, at least if you live in a place with a big library, like, I don't know, the greatest city in the whole world, where you have several libraries.
Speaker 0: They got the, you know, the physical media that is unencumbered by any bullshit, but then you don't have to store it in your house.
Speaker 0: You get the physical media, you can rip a copy if you want, if you can get through whatever, you know, DRMs are on there, which you definitely can.
Speaker 0: And then you give it back!
Speaker 0: Or you watch it and give it back!
Speaker 1: I feel like what we're gonna have to do as well, in terms of watching things that we own, will increasingly be to retreat behind Plex and things like it, like the old days.
Speaker 1: Private networks.
Speaker 0: That seems to be what's happening these days.
Speaker 0: Every nerd group has one friend who runs the Plex server, and everyone else logs in, and there's a collection of basically every movie or TV show that any nerd actually fucking cares about.
Speaker 0: And the nerd who runs the Plex server is constantly pirating and dumping new shit in there as it comes out, for the benefit of the rest of the group.
Speaker 0: So if you do not have- Every group has a person who is basically in the community who's sharing the contents with the other people who are "that persons".
Speaker 0: All those "that persons" who run the Plex servers are together, and they each bring the bounty home to their family.
Speaker 1: That is the real internet, I think, the way things are going.
Speaker 1: Things like that.
Speaker 1: If you do not know anyone who runs the Plex, or there's a lot of ways to do it, Plex is just one option, then consider becoming the person who runs it for your friends.
Speaker 1: The
Speaker 0: Plex is actually starting to, like, you know, the people who make the Plex software, who obviously are not engaged in any of the piracy whatsoever, they're doing the, you know, "Hey, you can open up Plex and pay like five bucks to watch a movie, just like, you know, instead of using, you know, Prime or YouTube or
Speaker 0: whatever.".
Speaker 0: I do think it's actually, you know, if you're willing to pay money to watch a movie at home, legally, it is interesting how all of these streaming deals where, like, you pay a flat fee and you get a huge blob of stuff that you can watch that's constantly changing.
Speaker 1: Yep, 99% of which you won't watch.
Speaker 0: They have all these exclusivities, right, where it's like, "Yes, you can only watch this on Netflix, you can only watch this on Hulu, and only this on
Speaker 0: whatever.".
Speaker 0: But paying X dollars to rent a movie, in the United States at least, it's like when a movie hits that point where it's available for digital renting or digital buying, right, it's on Prime, it's on iTunes, it's on YouTube, it's on Plex apparently.
Speaker 1: We watch most movies that way, we just rent it from, like, Amazon, we watch it.
Speaker 0: If you got money, it works, right?
Speaker 0: But it's interesting that there's no exclusivity with that, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, any movie, even if it's a Disney movie or whatever, is available on fucking everything if you're willing to pay 5 bucks.
Speaker 0: It's like, use any platform you want, they don't have deals.
Speaker 1: And so far, because I have bought a lot of things on Amazon, like bought the video, the digital one, they've never gotten rid of anything I've bought, even if it's not currently re-buyable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like
Speaker 0: people do worry that you're gonna lose them, which is obviously a legitimate fear, as we've just described in our news, but, you know, I've bought a very small handful of things on, like, Amazon Prime Video as opposed to just paying the few dollars for the rental.
Speaker 0: But the very few that I've paid for the permanent, you know, whatever, they're still there.
Speaker 0: They've never taken one away.
Speaker 0: They could.
Speaker 1: How often do you need the permanent?
Speaker 1: Like, the things I would buy permanently are the same things I would buy in physical media.
Speaker 1: The rare thing that I expect to re-watch many times over the course of my life, show to people, it's important to me, 99% of movies, no matter how good they are, I'm gonna watch them once, and maybe, like, five years later, I watch them again with someone who hasn't seen them before, or because I have some reason to watch them again.
Speaker 1: Things of the day!
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: So, you know, we like to come up with ideas for art installations we'll never make, and, of course, while some of our ideas may be okay, the real ones are usually 10 billion times better than the people actually, you know, people actually do it, or way better than us who just think and don't do anything.
Speaker 0: And so here's one that's, like, the best one I've seen in a while.
Speaker 0: What they did is they made a little cardboard, like, house, kind of, just like a room, or an enclosed space made of cardboard and wood.
Speaker 0: And basically it's just wooden, you know, grid, and then cardboard panels, right, in the grid.
Speaker 0: And if you stand on the outside of the structure, all of the cardboard is, like, each panel has, like, a little animation on it, where there's other pieces of cardboard that are perhaps colored and are moving around in a cool way.
Speaker 0: And it's like, "Ooh, that looks pretty
Speaker 0: cool!".
Speaker 0: And some of them are, like, combined together.
Speaker 0: It's like, there's one that's a little face, where there's, like, two panels or eyes, and a couple other panels or a mouth, and they move around.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you're looking at this little room, and on the outside, there's all this moving cardboard that's moving in fascinating, cool and artistic ways.
Speaker 0: And it's like, "Well, what's on the inside of
Speaker 0: this?".
Speaker 0: Right, because you can go in.
Speaker 0: If you go on the inside, you will see that behind every panel is some sort of, right, marble-run-esque Rube Goldberg-ish mechanism.
Speaker 0: And in order to make the outside part animate, you have to physically pick up some sand with a scoop, and dump it in the top, and the sand will fall down with the power of gravity, and spin the necessary parts that need spinning, with, you know, like, little whatever-you-called, you know, waterwheel-type mechanisms, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then that is what is powering the animations that happen on the outside.
Speaker 0: So if nobody's inside dumping sand, nothing's moving.
Speaker 1: It strikes me that part of the artistry of this is that if you're the one dumping the sand, you can't see it, so you have to work with someone else to see what's going on.
Speaker 0: I guess so.
Speaker 1: I mean, you might be able to load it up with sand and then run around and see what it was doing, depending on which- One matches up with the other, and how each, you know, so, this is a very amazing construction.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, my thing of the day is a 31-minute video that goes through- That's a long video.
Speaker 1: Well, because it goes through the full history of goalie masks in hockey, from nothing to now.
Speaker 0: From nothing to Jason is gonna kill you with his- Yup.
Speaker 0: Hey, Bart, check out my cool chainsaw hockey mask.
Speaker 1: But, one, if you're not a fan of ice hockey, you have to understand that the idea of, like, players wearing helmets is pretty new compared to the sport of hockey.
Speaker 1: Like, hockey masks were fucking terrifying looking until very recently in hockey history.
Speaker 1: If you think the Jason mask is crazy, look at what they were wearing in, like, the 30s.
Speaker 1: This stuff is terrifying, but the thing- the only thing that is more terrifying than that is Sawchuck's face from the era where they didn't wear any mask.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But this video is really good.
Speaker 1: It gets into every detail.
Speaker 1: It's every mask with examples and video, and it is just- there's a lot going on here.
Speaker 1: This video was fascinating.
Speaker 1: We started watching it thinking, "Oh, that looks cool," and we didn't realize it was 30 minutes long, and we didn't notice it was 30 minutes long until it ended.
Speaker 0: Okay, well.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment, the Geek Nights Book Club book is The Night Is Short.
Speaker 1: Walk on, girl.
Speaker 0: I should really get back to reading it, but I'm doing too much other shit right now.
Speaker 1: What I'm appreciating about it is that there was clearly a moral, or at least a theme, let's not say a moral, but a theme in the movie, around the guy thinks he's the main character, but he's not.
Speaker 1: And the girl is just living her life, but she's the main character of that night.
Speaker 1: Like, it's her story.
Speaker 1: It's her night.
Speaker 1: And there's a pretty good, like, not to spoil the book or the movie, but that's one of the core themes of it.
Speaker 1: It is way more on the nose, the allegory of who the main character is and what that means in the book compared to the movie.
Speaker 1: The movie doesn't really hit you over the head with the implications of this concept until later.
Speaker 1: The book, the guy, when it gets back to his narration, is like, "Yeah, I wasn't the main character, and I should have realized that at the time.
Speaker 1: She's the main character.
Speaker 1: It's all about
Speaker 1: her.".
Speaker 1: And it really just dives right into that theme.
Speaker 1: That's the only notable difference I'm seeing so far.
Speaker 1: It's a good book.
Speaker 1: I'm enjoying it.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty quick read, I think, too.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, we will be live at PAX East with at least one panel that is actually, and this is such a all-new panel, that even Scott will not disagree when I say this is all new content.
Speaker 0: I cannot say that this panel is not an all-new panel.
Speaker 0: However, it will obviously contain many of Geeknight's favorite game-like talking points.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 1: what it's probably not gonna contain, though, is heuristics.
Speaker 0: Probably not, nope.
Speaker 0: No heuristics this time.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I feel like we've beaten that heuristic horse to death, so I think that'll be fine.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty excited about this one, so come see us at PAX East.
Speaker 1: This is brand new stuff.
Speaker 1: We're gonna video it, as we always do, but, you know, it's possible.
Speaker 1: the two cameras fall over, or, like, PAX burns down and the video doesn't get out, so... The only way to guarantee you'll hear what we have to say about all games being the same game is to be in our panel room at PAX East, and I will post our scheduled time as soon as I get a chance.
Speaker 1: I don't think we have any other meta.
Speaker 1: Just dive right in, 'cause I'm already pretty hungry for dinner.
Speaker 1: We, in the old days of Geeknights, whenever we went to a con, we'd do an episode talking about that con, and we went to a lot of cons.
Speaker 0: Well, oftentimes you were going to a con we hadn't been to before.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: We also...
Speaker 0: Like, "Hey, what's this con
Speaker 0: like?".
Speaker 0: Give you the vibe, whether you should know if you should go to it or not.
Speaker 1: We used to also be like, "Ah, shit, Otacon's coming up,".
Speaker 1: and we'd do, like, a Otacon preview, and then we'd do, like, a show about the Otacon we were at.
Speaker 1: And then the next few...
Speaker 0: Didn't have any other things to talk about.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But also, that was an error when we did Geeknights four nights a week, and we almost never skipped an episode, and we just needed content.
Speaker 0: Nothing else to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Nowadays, we go to a lot fewer cons.
Speaker 1: Like, we are really picky about the cons we go to.
Speaker 0: We could go to some more, but it's just a hassle.
Speaker 1: I might expand a little bit, but it's situational, but, like, it's mostly PAXes and Magfests.
Speaker 1: And also, we don't do a show about every con we go to.
Speaker 0: They all kind of blur together.
Speaker 0: They're pretty much the same every year.
Speaker 0: It's like, "Oh, I went to PAXes this year.
Speaker 0: It's basically the same exact thing as last year, only different
Speaker 0: games.".
Speaker 1: It's been the same exact thing since...
Speaker 0: Also, some repeat.
Speaker 1: Since 2011, because 2010, it was weird, because it was in the Hinds, and also it was new.
Speaker 1: But it's worth talking about this Super Magfest and reviewing it specifically, I think, and I got a few reasons for this.
Speaker 1: One, I love PAXes, but Magfest, Super Magfest in particular, really is unique in a lot of ways.
Speaker 1: And its uniqueness, as we emerge from the dark times, has not only been heightened, but, like, Magfest is on an upward trajectory.
Speaker 1: This was the best Magfest I've ever attended.
Speaker 1: Not counting weird Magfests before they moved to the Gaylord, which were better in some ways, but also, you can't make cons like that anymore, just for a lot of reasons that we don't really have time to get into.
Speaker 1: Like, that was a different kind of thing back when it was just in one hotel and there weren't that many people there.
Speaker 1: But also, over the years, we always joked that this Magfest might be the last, and for those of you who have not listened to Geek Nights forever, I think it's worth explaining what we meant by that, because we talked about that many, many, many years ago.
Speaker 1: But basically, Magfest is, because it's unique, it has a lot of unique risks that other anime cons don't have and PAXes don't have.
Speaker 1: Like, Magfest grasps for a lot.
Speaker 1: Their reach is broad.
Speaker 1: And the more you reach, the more you risk the hubris.
Speaker 0: Grasp exceed grasp.
Speaker 1: Poseidon comes down and fucks your shit up because you spread yourself too thin.
Speaker 1: You tried to do too much, you went too big.
Speaker 1: And in the early days of big Magfest, when they moved into the Gaylord, it was a little touch and go.
Speaker 1: Like, I was really worried Magfest would have an incident that fucked it over and caused it to shut down.
Speaker 1: And every year that Magfest continued, I was delighted, because I could not imagine, as an adult who is a product manager who knows things about business and the world, the risks Magfest would take on to be able to do the amazing shit it did seemed insurmountable.
Speaker 0: So, I mean, first of all, it's a non-profit, right?
Speaker 0: Which is true of many cons, including anime cons.
Speaker 0: However, if you lose your non-profit status, basically the whole thing is over.
Speaker 1: It's game over, man.
Speaker 0: It's like this one linchpin.
Speaker 0: If that happens, suddenly they have to pay all these taxes.
Speaker 0: If the non-profit status is revoked, it's over.
Speaker 0: The end.
Speaker 1: Like, I wrote a 1.5 page attestation in my professional opinion that I signed and submitted to the states to advocate for my belief that Magfest deserves its 501(c)(3) charter.
Speaker 1: That it is, in fact, a valuable non-profit, because they had some trouble many years ago, and they needed to... And they survived it.
Speaker 1: They are a non-profit.
Speaker 1: They've succeeded, they've kept this, it's going fine.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But it can always be challenged or lost, basically at any time.
Speaker 0: So if any kind of incident happens that draws the eye of whoever, you know, whatever government agency or whatever, IRS, whoever, onto Magfest, and the evil eye appears, and they don't like what they see, based on which bureaucrat that eye belongs to, that could be the end, right?
Speaker 0: And because Magfest runs 24/7 for four days, and is a drunken wild fiesta, with children running around and all sorts of nonsense, the odds of something happening that would draw someone's eye to be like, a music festival, a non-profit, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, higher than with, say, a small anime con that does not draw a big crowd, that is not 24/7, that is only three days.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like, there are rowdier cons, but they're a lot smaller.
Speaker 1: And there are larger cons, but they're not as rowdy in the convention center itself.
Speaker 0: Or they're for-profit.
Speaker 0: In which case, the eye cannot be upon them, because they're already paying taxes.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And also, for-profits tend to have a lot more money and logistical resources from professionals, as opposed to an army of volunteers doing their best to make this con happen.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: There's also insurance, right?
Speaker 0: Every con, profit or non-profit, has insurance, and if you lose your insurance, you're done, just like you are, right?
Speaker 0: So, if the insurance agents, the master Keaton's, don't like what they see happening at this event, and they say there is a high risk of something happening at this event, that we would have to, you know, we would have to honor a claim for, we will either not refuse to insure you, or jack up your premiums a bunch, and that would also potentially kill the event, that has somehow not happened.
Speaker 0: I don't know if all the actuaries just haven't actually gone to Magfest, I don't know what's going on there.
Speaker 0: Um, but that is another risk.
Speaker 1: Well, I think there's a few things, I think there's actually a few things going on there.
Speaker 1: And again, this is all just our outsider speculation, like, we're not staff at Magfest, we just do panels and a tent.
Speaker 0: We are not privy to any actual things happening with regards to these issues, these are just things that are true for all conventions, and therefore, logically, must be true for Magfest as well, and looks us.
Speaker 1: Yup, the only convention we have deep insider insights about was Kineticon, because we ran like the entire, all the programming on one of the floors for like nine years.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about what the actual business people at Magfest are doing, or saying, I don't even know who they are, I don't know, I have no inside facts whatsoever, this is just outside observations as an attendee, and person who knows more than nothing about conventions.
Speaker 1: So this year was the first full-on Magfest since the pandemic and the dark times started to wind down.
Speaker 1: And based on how PAX Unplugged went, because PAX Unplugged projected a certain number of people, it was the first PAX Unplugged that was full-on since the pandemic started winding down.
Speaker 1: And that PAX Unplugged, like, sold out, had ridiculous attendance, was the most crowded PAX I think I've ever been to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's like what happened was, is obviously, you know, that first PAX East that was like as the pandemic was beginning, was eerie and quiet, right?
Speaker 0: Compared to others, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like, how much of that was, but people, you know, paid for hotels and badges way before that PAX, right?
Speaker 0: So it was like, was it really that pandemic that was keeping people away from that PAX East in 2020, right?
Speaker 0: Or was it people winding down, right?
Speaker 0: You know, the industry being less interested, etc.
Speaker 0: And so then obviously there was the cancellation era, right, where the conventions weren't happening.
Speaker 0: Then there was the sort of, we're going to have the convention with all sorts of mask rules and, right, but people are still afraid to come out era.
Speaker 1: Like, you didn't go to many of those.
Speaker 1: I went to a bunch of them, but the way I went to them was driving myself, double masking, going into the con, doing a panel, immediately leaving.
Speaker 0: Right, but I mean, what did, you know, you weren't there for very long.
Speaker 1: Nope, and they were really sedate and kind of sparse and really quiet and, yeah, so.
Speaker 0: So now we've reached the point where it's like, okay, people have basically given up and it's like, well, we weren't sure.
Speaker 0: It's like, are people going to be, you know, is there going to be?
Speaker 0: a people realized, ah, I didn't go to conventions and actually I was happy or not going.
Speaker 0: Why was I wasting my time on that and stop going and treat it as a transition point in life away from the con scene, which I could totally see.
Speaker 0: I'm sure people did that.
Speaker 0: Or are people going to see this as, haha, I haven't conned in a while.
Speaker 0: It's like, it's fresh again.
Speaker 1: And now we know in retrospect, we have the hindsight.
Speaker 1: So it was definitely the latter.
Speaker 1: This magfest was the first one ever to sell out in the game.
Speaker 0: I'm sure for some people it was the former, but it seems like for most people it was the latter.
Speaker 0: And I think also you can't discount the fact that for some people who, you know, I guess there weren't cons or weren't strong cons for a few years.
Speaker 0: Like if you were, you know, 13 in 2020, you're now 17, 18.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, this might be like, boom, I can con now.
Speaker 0: I was waiting my whole life.
Speaker 0: And then I got, I got blocked, but now I can do it.
Speaker 0: And then those people show up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Imagine we went to Otacon in 2002 and 2003 and we couldn't go again until 2009.
Speaker 1: Like what would that feel like?
Speaker 0: You also have to consider the economic situation, right?
Speaker 0: Where it's like, you know, people seem to say, I don't know, but there seems to be this common talk that companies over hired during the pandemic.
Speaker 0: And that's part of why they're laying off now.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But it's like, well, if they over hired, then that's would explain there being more people with money to go to cons.
Speaker 0: They weren't spending that money on cons for a while, but they were working and now there's cons again.
Speaker 0: And so that another possible explanation of what's going on.
Speaker 1: So we came into the Super Mag Fest in a situation where before we get there, we know it's selling out.
Speaker 1: That has never happened.
Speaker 0: We already knew it was going to sell out.
Speaker 1: So it's going to be the biggest Mag Fest that has ever happened.
Speaker 0: We know it was big since the since the hotel rush.
Speaker 1: But it's going to be the biggest Mag Fest and the most crowded Mag Fest ever after several years of staff attrition and staff difficulties from the pandemic.
Speaker 1: And like you haven't run a full Mag Fest in a few years because of all these situations.
Speaker 1: So possibly less experienced staff and more new staff, more turnover, possibly some loss of expertise because you haven't done a full on one in a while.
Speaker 1: Also the most crowded.
Speaker 1: And yet it was simultaneously the best run, smoothest Mag Fest I have ever seen.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: And it was significantly upgraded from prior Mag Fest.
Speaker 1: The staff were more present.
Speaker 1: There were more staff.
Speaker 1: The staff were more professional and more capable.
Speaker 1: Not saying they weren't professional.
Speaker 0: I didn't really encounter staff.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: I did quite a bit, but partly because I was talking to a lot of them.
Speaker 1: But I saw more.
Speaker 1: There were more staff in the panel rooms.
Speaker 1: A lot of aspects of the con got upgraded just in general, which we'll talk about those a little bit.
Speaker 1: So if the biggest, riskiest Mag Fest to ever happen also was the best run Mag Fest ever happened, then Mag Fest clearly is on an upward trend of every possible metric in all the good ways.
Speaker 1: So if you've never been to Mag Fest, fucking go next year.
Speaker 1: It's one of the best cons there is.
Speaker 0: If you can.
Speaker 1: If you can.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's hard even if you have a bunch of money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like it is really hard to get a hotel.
Speaker 1: It's really it's going to be hard to get a badge, I think, next year.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, for sure.
Speaker 1: So Mag Fest was fucking amazing.
Speaker 1: So let's step through a little bit of what made it so fucking amazing.
Speaker 1: And then when I run out of steam because I'm hungry, we'll end the show.
Speaker 0: Well, first of all, all the areas of Mag Fest.
Speaker 0: you expect to be there.
Speaker 0: We're still there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But each area felt like it's like in the previous Mag Fest, it felt like there were some areas that were sparse or sad while other areas were banging.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: At this Mag Fest, they had all the same areas plus at least a couple of new things.
Speaker 0: And all of them were basically at least the times that I was awake.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Were at full power other than, I guess, the dealer's room at night when people close up their booths.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But even then, there was a weird number of because I went out late and you didn't.
Speaker 1: There were, I'd say about a tenth of the dealers were open at two forty five in the morning.
Speaker 1: Like I saw them.
Speaker 1: It was kind of amazing.
Speaker 0: But, you know, we talked about the MIBs being upgraded, but basically that applied to all the other areas as well.
Speaker 1: The arcade had the highest percentage of machines working of any Mag Fest I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: It had the same beautiful variety as ever.
Speaker 1: There were so many DDR machines, I didn't even have to wait to play DDR.
Speaker 0: Like there were there was a shit ton of pinballs, but it's like you could get in there maybe.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You might have to wait for like one person.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: The panel rooms, like the panels were getting a lot of attendance.
Speaker 1: Like people are going to panels again at conventions or at least at Mag Fest.
Speaker 0: And it depends on which one.
Speaker 0: It was actually in the panel area.
Speaker 0: It was actually surprisingly at this one room that was for a speed run thing, Mag Fast.
Speaker 0: And meanwhile, GDQ was happening at the same time as Mag Fest.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And yet that little Mag Fast room was rocking basically 24/7.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: One of our panels was next to that room and you could hear people just yelling from the speed run room periodically during our panel.
Speaker 0: They didn't waste any space at Mag Fest with things like table flipping charity or whatever.
Speaker 0: The only real waste of space is that giant room they use for registration.
Speaker 0: The queue room or whatever.
Speaker 0: But it's like, OK, I guess, you know, it's not a waste at the time.
Speaker 0: It's you being used.
Speaker 0: It's just the rest of the con.
Speaker 1: It's the kind of room that like after the first two days, they could possibly transform it into something else, maybe in the future.
Speaker 1: They even used.
Speaker 1: So at the end of one of the long hallways, the convention center, there's an area that's just kind of like an open area, like a big alcove.
Speaker 0: So in the past, that's where the speed run type stuff was.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But they moved.
Speaker 0: they moved it into a room.
Speaker 1: So what they set up over there is a whole bunch of chairs and they had a area called the soapbox, which has existed at Mag Fest before.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's always been a Mag Fest.
Speaker 1: But it's never existed with this scale.
Speaker 1: And it was rocking.
Speaker 1: And the people there were not bad people.
Speaker 1: Like I saw some like it was nothing bad was happening over there.
Speaker 1: For the brief time that you were there, I was over there several times and I was actually.
Speaker 1: I actually stood in line to give a talk.
Speaker 1: I was going to give a talk on.
Speaker 1: I was going to give the audience a choice.
Speaker 1: I'm either going to talk about communism for 15 minutes or I'll tell you the story about the time a wild pack of dogs almost tried to almost attack me in Istanbul at night.
Speaker 0: And if they know, I thought you were going to talk about the the like the you know, the area next to that, where there was the all physical related activities, dancing, yoga in that area was fantastic.
Speaker 1: But every event I wanted to go in there was full because it was super popular.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Also, they had the Lockpick Village like you see at Defcon.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So that was this is the new thing, right?
Speaker 0: So down in the you know, the bottom area of Mag Fest in the in the Christmas Village Hotel weird zone, there was some side rooms that I've never seen used at Mag Fest before.
Speaker 1: Never cool because that area was like under renovation.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know what those rooms I never knew what the hell those rooms.
Speaker 1: That whole area was got like renovated and I don't think it was available for Mag Fest use until this.
Speaker 0: Who knows what whether it was or not.
Speaker 0: But regardless, in these rooms that I had never seen used before, there was basically they basically made arts and crafts zone.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it was all sorts of makerspace action, arts and crafts action, all sorts of workshop stuff at all these tables and a Lockpick Village all in the same place where like you could they just had lock pick practice tools and locks.
Speaker 1: You could just sit down and, you know, that room was especially notable because they had the sewing workshops in there.
Speaker 1: They had everything.
Speaker 1: But what was most notable about is one, it was completely packed the entire con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was hard to go like if you just wanted to go in there and make a little fart and crap, get a seat in there.
Speaker 1: But two, it's pretty rare for a con to add a new kind of room and have it be so well done the first year.
Speaker 0: Like it might have been there when we weren't there.
Speaker 1: But not but it was.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it was or not.
Speaker 1: It definitely wasn't there when the last big Mag Fest we went to.
Speaker 0: If it was, I think it could have.
Speaker 0: this might not have been the first year.
Speaker 0: For it.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: You know, we don't know.
Speaker 1: We're not going to talk about the games of Mag Fest because they were so good at Mavs that we did an entire extra episode that I'll just link to a couple of days ago, you know, and the tabletop zone of Mag Fest.
Speaker 0: It's like, look, it's not as good as the tabletop zone.
Speaker 0: It packs and obviously not as good as tabletop and unplugged because unplugged is entirely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's 100 percent of unplugged.
Speaker 0: But for as their library, man, but it was, you know, well run.
Speaker 0: It just wasn't extensive.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It has a tiny panel room.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: It was 100 percent full in there.
Speaker 0: Hard to get a seat at all hours.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was rocking in there.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So people were playing tabletop games like mad.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: People were doing everything like mad, like this Mag Fest was maximized in every regard and every area was getting a lot of attention from the attendees.
Speaker 1: But despite all this.
Speaker 1: Something else was different.
Speaker 1: I will charitably say that at the peak of Mag Fest before the pandemic, after about midnight, there would be roving gangs of drunk people who were extremely annoying and you had to kind of avoid them.
Speaker 1: When you're navigating the con.
Speaker 1: I did not encounter that at any point in this Mag Fest, like the late night was really crowded and really rocking out until around three
Speaker 1: a.m.,
Speaker 1: which was the latest.
Speaker 1: I stayed up multiple nights.
Speaker 1: It was really rocking.
Speaker 1: It was really crowded, but everyone was chill.
Speaker 1: Everyone was having a good time.
Speaker 1: Like it was oddly sedate for how energized the crowd was in a way that I have never seen at Mag Fest at two forty five in the morning in the past.
Speaker 0: Even in the concert zones of the chiptune zones, which usually would attract a rowdy group.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Everyone was behaving extremely appropriately.
Speaker 0: that I saw with my eyes.
Speaker 0: And it's like, you know, for as much as we talked about all of our society be having more antisocial behaviors, Mag Fest, you know, I guess pushed in the opposite direction.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Basically, we keep talking about, like, you know, the good Internet and the bad Internet's.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like Mag Fest was like a real world manifestation of the good Internet.
Speaker 1: It's always is a physical.
Speaker 1: I think it's literally that what you said.
Speaker 1: It is a physical manifestation of the things on the Internet that we like and we support and we wish society was more like.
Speaker 0: You know, so it's.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: it's an art festival.
Speaker 1: It's a social festival like Mag Fest is actually becoming a cultural touchstone, I think.
Speaker 0: If going to PAX is like going to IGN dot com.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Going to Mag Fest is like going to itch.io.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's what like everything was just great at the con.
Speaker 1: I also encountered something that was kind of amazing.
Speaker 1: And it's such a weird coincidence that I just have to tell the story.
Speaker 1: So years ago, our friend Chase, who if you if you've been to Mag Fest, there's actually a decent chance.
Speaker 1: you have met our friend Chase.
Speaker 1: Cool bald dude with some facial hair who might just like pull you into a game of spotted and teach you how to play and then make you play it with him.
Speaker 1: So one year he couldn't go to Mag Fest.
Speaker 1: So we all like a bunch of us put on bald caps and fake facial hair and wandered around the con as the chase gang yelling at people to play spotted.
Speaker 1: We did a whole like cosplay thing at this Mag Fest.
Speaker 1: I saw a whole bunch of people wearing green pants, facial hair and bald wigs roaming around the con.
Speaker 1: I took a picture.
Speaker 1: I'm even sharing the picture.
Speaker 0: That was a joke from an MMO.
Speaker 0: I forget which MMO it was, but it's basically an inside joke from an MMO.
Speaker 0: Or some kind of meme or something like that.
Speaker 1: We had a bald guy facial hair cosplay with spotted one year.
Speaker 1: That was our private inside joke at this Mag Fest.
Speaker 0: It's a RuneScape joke.
Speaker 0: That's what it is.
Speaker 1: So this group had a RuneScape inside joke.
Speaker 1: that is bald cap, facial hair.
Speaker 1: But instead of spotted, they were carrying axes.
Speaker 1: So we stopped them and they explained what they were doing and we explained what we did with the chase gang and they thought that was delightful and they started telling people we are the chase gang.
Speaker 0: I didn't see them do that.
Speaker 0: I saw them making their RuneScape jokes.
Speaker 1: So I got a bunch of pictures with them and one of them emailed me because I gave him my business card.
Speaker 1: This Mag Fest was just fantastic and it's hard to really overstate that.
Speaker 0: One more thing I got to say about it though, that was really shocking to me, is that I saw many people there who were people from the olden days.
Speaker 0: There were a lot of people who were early Geek Nights listeners, people I knew from back in the day who I hadn't seen at cons, even before the dark times.
Speaker 0: Who I hadn't seen at cons in the late 2010s at all.
Speaker 1: Like convention friends or people who used to work for us as staff at Kineticon.
Speaker 0: Someone came up to me and said they recognized me from RIT Anime Club.
Speaker 0: They're like, "Did you go to
Speaker 0: RIT?".
Speaker 0: They're like, "I remember you from the Anime Club.
Speaker 0: I didn't remember them at
Speaker 0: all.".
Speaker 0: And it's like, they didn't know me from Geek Nights, they didn't know me from panels, they didn't know me from cons.
Speaker 0: I'm like,
Speaker 0: "Alright.".
Speaker 1: Matt, one of the guys we used to do panels at, we used to be at Kineticon and we'd hang out with and it was in the Geek Nights forums.
Speaker 1: He did a panel on Kurosawa.
Speaker 1: that actually was fantastic and I learned a bunch of things I didn't know.
Speaker 1: It was a really good panel.
Speaker 1: I bumped into a whole bunch of Mag Fest staff who were and in some cases still are Kineticon staff.
Speaker 1: I don't want to say gratifying.
Speaker 1: I want to say I'm proud but not in a patronizing way.
Speaker 1: It is cool to see people who helped us make Kineticon as good as it could be out there making Mag Fest as good as it could be and reconnecting with them after all these years.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying, there was definitely an aspect of people coming back.
Speaker 0: They were tired of, these were people I hadn't seen at cons, so either life circumstances or whatever kept them away, then dark times kept them away, but then they came back.
Speaker 1: And I think it's part of a broader narrative.
Speaker 1: I think there's a story here and it ties back to what we were talking about in the beginning.
Speaker 1: What happens at conventions, the reason we went to anime cons, anime was a part of it, but really it was that you get to experience some of the friendships and social spaces that rarely exist in the real world at scale.
Speaker 1: And you primarily experience online or in very cloistered environments like colleges and we all miss that for a while and we seek that out in society.
Speaker 1: I wish my daily life were a little bit more like Mag Fest.
Speaker 1: Not a lot pit, I got to sleep and do things other than mag, but I'd like my social world to be a little more like Mag Fest.
Speaker 0: I got one negative thing to say about Mag Fest, it's still fucking cold.
Speaker 0: Wouldn't Mag Fest be absolutely incredible if it was warm?
Speaker 0: It would be the best.
Speaker 0: If it was somehow warm during Mag Fest, it would be unbelievable.
Speaker 1: The only negative thing I can say about Mag Fest is good fucking luck getting a badge or a hotel next year.
Speaker 1: There's nothing we can do about that, but that's a whole other problem that we've talked about on like 20 different episodes of Geek Nights about 10 different things.
Speaker 1: I don't think we need to belabor that point.
Speaker 1: Alright, I'm hungry, I think we'll drop off here.
Speaker 1: So Mag Fest, like, good job, keep doing it.
Speaker 0: Try to go to it, good luck.
Speaker 1: Yep, and I wanna, I'm gonna try it, I think I wanna contribute more to Mag Fest and if we, I wanna start doing more panels like we used to do in the old days with mages and everything.
Speaker 1: I'll do 10 panels if it gets a bunch of people to go into panel rooms.
Speaker 0: Eh, I wanna enjoy my Mag Fest.
Speaker 1: Oh, I mean, old Mag Fest, like for every mages panel you did, I always did like three.
Speaker 1: There's all those videos of like.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna panel with a bunch of not-scots.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowclue.com for show notes, discussion, links and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays, gaming and games.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are animation and comics.
Speaker 1: Thursdays are arbitrary and indiscriminate.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are... Alan Joyce, Link Iggy, Drew Edd, Lily Tenebrae Case, Karen Makes Music, Chris Hadad, Christopher Orr, Clinton Walton, Finn, Joel Hayes, Penny Rymer, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Horrell, and tons of people whose names I will not say at their request or because they're below that very low threshold of five dollars.
Speaker 1: Giving perhaps a pound or a euro or even a dollar.
Speaker 1: But anyway, yeah, we're gonna be at PAX East.
Speaker 1: It's probably gonna be completely packed and a good time.
Speaker 1: Uh, we don't really have any other conventions planned.
Speaker 1: If there's any conventions that you think we should go to that we have not been to, either tell the convention or at least tell us and we'll see if it fits.
Speaker 1: But for now, I simply leave you tonight with... "If video will return after these messaging...".
Speaker 0: "Waking up with this cereal is hot
Speaker 0: stuff!".
Speaker 0: "Flavor take your oatmeal, waking up your taste, hot
Speaker 1: "Apple, raisin, cinnamon, and maple brown
Speaker 1: sugar!".
Speaker 1: "Hot
Speaker 1: stuff!".
Speaker 1: "Flavor take your oatmeal,
Speaker 1: H-O-T-S-T-U-S-S!".
Speaker 1: "It's sweet, it's smooth, it's hot, hot
Speaker 1: stuff!".
Speaker 1: "Sweetness and cream, great taste, apple and cinnamon, great
Speaker 1: taste!".
Speaker 1: "H-O-T-S-T-U-S-S hot
Speaker 1: stuff!".
Speaker 1: "Flavor take your oatmeal, it's hot, hot
Speaker 1: "Flavor take your oatmeal, the hot part of a complete
Speaker 1: breakfast!".